<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vitor Mafra</title>
    <link>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vitor Mafra</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:31:40 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Books with Drauzio</title>
      <link>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/blog/drauzio_varella_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:31:40 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/blog/drauzio_varella_books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finally finished reading all 20 books by Drauzio Varella.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/about_me/cv/images/drauzio_varella_books.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;All 20 Drauzio&#39;s books&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-size: 0.85rem; color: #666; margin-top: 8px; margin-bottom: 0; text-align: center; font-style: italic; opacity: 0.8;&#34;&gt;All 20 Drauzio&#39;s books&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started years ago with his trilogy about the Brazilian prison system, and it completely hooked me. A while later, after reading his book about running, I decided I would read everything he published. It took time (and I obviously mixed these readings with a lot of completely unrelated books along the way), but I kept coming back to his work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Lady Gaga fans taught me about LLMs</title>
      <link>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/blog/lady_gaga_llms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 17:24:29 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/blog/lady_gaga_llms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/about_me/cv/images/lady_gaga_rio.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Lady Gaga concert in Rio&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-size: 0.85rem; color: #666; margin-top: 8px; margin-bottom: 0; text-align: center; font-style: italic; opacity: 0.8;&#34;&gt;My girlfriend and I in Rio de Janeiro one day before the historical Lady Gaga in Copacabana concert&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I found myself working on a technically ambitious project with an unexpectedly emotional motivation: build a system capable of competing in a large trivia event where the prize was a pair of VIP tickets to a Lady Gaga concert. The quiz promised fast-paced questions, a strict timer, and a scoring mechanism that rewarded not just accuracy, but the &lt;em&gt;speed&lt;/em&gt; of each response. And after speaking with one of the organizers, I confirmed something crucial: online searches and external tools were explicitly allowed. The competition would be determined by reflexes and, of course, knowledge in Lady Gaga.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/about_me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first stepped into computer science driven by a fascination with how technology shapes societies and the belief that data-driven tools could improve people’s lives at scale. During my undergraduate years at UFMG, this curiosity evolved into a concrete mission: understanding how information flows online and how we can build systems that make the digital world more accessible, reliable, and fair. From early projects that scraped university restaurant menus to nationwide studies on misinformation, I learned that thoughtful engineering can ripple far beyond the screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appearances in the Media</title>
      <link>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/on_media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/on_media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-stuff&#34;&gt;Personal stuff&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One day, I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/ovitormafra/status/1626738854915891200&#34;&gt;short thread on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; (now X) offering a solution to find your friends in the crowded Brazilian Carnival (if you’ve never been, it’s &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; crowded). It went viral — ~800k people saw it, and two journalists reached out to me to talk about it. The solution is based on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://what3words.com&#34;&gt;really cool company&lt;/a&gt; that divided the entire world into 3m x 3m squares and assigned each one a unique sequence of three words. All I did was connect the dots, and it seems people really liked the idea. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running is pretty cool. I will write about this later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Minha primeira maratona&#34; src=&#34;https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/about_me/running/images/maratona_rio.jpeg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Minha primeira maratona&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;O livro que me apresentou à corrida&#34; src=&#34;https://vitor-mafra.github.io/about_me/about_me/running/images/autografo_drauzio.jpeg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;O livro que me apresentou à corrida (autografado ~5 anos depois)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
